《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我会逃出升天的
I'll find my way out.
因为这地方就是个大谜题
'Cause this place is just one big puzzle,
而谜题是我的特长
and puzzles are my forte.
天呐
Oh, my.
我都不认识你了
I don't know who you are anymore.
得了  这话太老套了
Oh, please, that is such a ridiculous cliché...
我该照顾好自己了
It's time for me to look out for number one.
雇"火柴"马龙杀你父母的人
The man who contracted Matches Malone to kill your parents
自称"哲学家"
called himself The Philosopher.
雨果·斯特兰奇  哲学家
Hugo Strange. The Philosopher.
我是逼迫托马斯·韦恩关闭这个项目的人之一
I was one of the ones who forced Thomas Wayne to shut down the program,
你在撒谎
You're lying.
我需要确定你就是幕后主使
I needed to be sure you were behind all this,
现在我确定了
and now I am.
我们的作品需要新的人格
Our creations need new personas
来集中他们的精神
to give their minds focus.
这把剑是昨天刚做的
That sword was made yesterday.
这件复制品对他接受新身份很关键
Our replica is central to his acceptance of his new identity.
我是死亡天使
I... am Azrael!
杜马我主
My Lord Dumas.
给我命令吧
Command me.
一个杀人犯现在自由在城市里游荡
A murderer walks the streets of this city a free man.
他必须被你的剑斩灭
By your blade, he must be destroyed.
告诉我他的名字
Tell me his name.
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon.
这不可能
That-that is not possible.
是你
You.
你死了
You're dead.
又活了
Not anymore.
条子来了  快看
Five-O, Five-O, come on, come on!
你们这是干什么
What is the meaning of this?
你们让病人不安了
You are upsetting the inmates.
你老板在哪  亲爱的
Where's your boss, darling?
我们有搜查令
We got a warrant
可以搜查他的办公室和里面的一切
to search his office and everything in it.
他正忙着应付病人
He's busy with patients.
没关系  皮博迪女士
That's quite all right, Ms. Peabody.
我们要把这里翻个底朝天  斯特兰奇
We're gonna tear this place apart, Strange.
我们会找到答案的
We're gonna get answers.
什么的答案
Answers to what?
记录表明西奥·盖勒文的尸体被送到这里
Records indicate Theo Galavan's dead body was brought here,
已经火化了
that it was cremated.
差不多
Seems likely.
那他昨晚怎么会出现在哥谭市警局
Then why the hell was he at the GCPD last night,
用一把剑刺穿了我们警监呢
running our captain through with a sword, huh?
我和你一样惊讶
I'm as surprised as you are.
顺便  和我解释一下
And while you're at it, explain to me this:
为什么同样最后出现在这儿的维克多·弗莱斯
why Victor Fries, also last seen here,
也是死透了  却穿得像个宇航员  还活蹦乱跳
very dead, is alive and kicking and dressed like a spaceman.
你有问题  斯特兰奇
You stink, Strange.
这整个地方都有问题
This whole damned place stinks.
借过
Excuse me.
这是你的办公室吗
Is this your office?
没错  但警探...
Yes, but, Detective, please...
什么...
What the...?
都粉碎了
Shredded?
该死的...
Son of a...
春季大扫除
Spring cleaning.
你们可以随便看看
You're free to look around.
我不确定还有什么东西可看
I'm just not sure there's much more to see.
你以为粉碎了一些文件就能平安无事了吗
You think shredding a few documents is gonna save you?
别做梦了
It won't.
我们盯上你了
We're on to you.
坏蛋进  怪物出
Bad guys come in and monsters come out.
就像松林农场  对吗
Just like Pinewood, right?
鉴于你已经不在警局工作
Seeing as how you no longer work for the police department,
我无须与你交谈
I'm not required to speak with you,
戈登先生
Mr. Gordon.
你满腔愤怒  詹姆斯·戈登
You have a lot of anger, James Gordon.
我可以帮你
I can help you with that.
我们要把这栋楼翻个底朝天
We're gonna tear this damn building apart,
不放过任何一个角落
every square inch!
看清楚你的搜查令  警探
Check your warrant, Detective.
上面清楚地写明你有权
It clearly states that you have permission
搜查我的办公室  仅此而已
to search my office, nothing more.
当然  如果你下次带着别的搜查令来
Of course, I'm more than happy to accommodate you
我会非常乐意配合的
if you come back with a different warrant.
顺便告诉你  我也会打电话给法官
Just know that I will also be calling the judge
告诉他让哥谭市警局
and telling him how disruptive it is to have the GCPD--
和其他闲杂人等
and others--
来这间康复之所游荡
traipsing about this place of healing
毫无必要地打扰病人清修  会造成多大破坏
and disrupting the patients unnecessarily.
这事没完
This ain't over yet.
阿泽瑞尔回来了吗
Has Azrael returned?
没
Nope.
令人不安
Troubling.
你怎么从病房里跑出来了
What are you doing out of your cell?
天大的错误
Big mistake.
抱歉  是我的错
Sorry, my bad.
我只是迷路了
Just got lost.
能送我回去吗
Escort me back, would you?
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你  祝你一天愉快
Thank you, have a nice day.
我必须离开这里
I've got to get out of here.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸Amy   Silence   DustD   charcie
翻译 大K   小酸奶!   草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
熊孩子
Damn kids.
你把锁撬开了吗
Did you break the lock?!
说你呢
Hey, you!
这里是上帝之家  朝拜圣地
This is God's house, a place of worship,
不是流浪汉收容所
not a homeless shelter.
赶快走  不然我就报警了
Get out before I call the cops.
我需要一件武器来完成我神圣的征途
I need a weapon to fulfill my holy quest.
我没有任何武器
I don't have any weapons.
那我要你何用
then what good are you?
哥谭
第二季  第二十集
昨晚遭受蒙面人暴力袭击后
Captain Nathaniel Barnes remains
纳撒尼尔·巴恩斯警监
in critical condition at Gotham General
现仍正在哥谭总院
after suffering a violent attack
处于生命垂危状态
by a masked assailant late last night.
目前尚未抓获任何嫌疑人
So far no arrests have been made,
但据处于封锁状态的哥谭市警局的内部消息
but reports coming from within the locked down GCPD
已经证实  此蒙面人正是
have confirmed that the masked man is, in fact,
哥谭前任市长西奥·盖勒文
former Gotham mayor Theo Galavan.
搜索彻夜进行
Search parties continued throughout the night,
但迄今为止
but, as of yet,
盖勒文的下落仍是一个谜
Galavan's whereabouts remain a mystery.
你逃不了的  盖勒文
There's nowhere to hide, Galavan.
我不会放过你的
I'm coming for you.
阿尔瓦雷斯  找到他了吗
Alvarez, any sign of him yet?
没有  但我们派出了六架直升机
No, but we've got six choppers in the air
和全州所有的嗅探犬
and every sniffer dog in the state out there looking.
联系州北的头头
Call the brass upstate,
叫他们多派些人来
tell them to get more men down here.
那怪物绝对跑不远的
That freak couldn't have gotten far.
汤姆  给法官打电话
Tom, get Judge Bam Bam on the phone.
告诉他我需要新搜查阿卡姆的搜查令
Tell him I need a new warrant to search Arkham,
要搜所有的屋子
every friggin' room, all of it!
他们在干什么
What are they all doing?
他们没了警监  哈维
They don't have a captain, Harvey.
看来该你上了
Guess you're it.
我可不是警监
I ain't no captain.
对他们说点什么
Say something to them.
我不在这里工作了  你在
I don't work here anymore, you do.
好吧  大家伙  听好了
All right, everyone, listen up.
我知道我们现在都有点惊恐
I know we're all a bit freaked out right now.
这可以理解
It's understandable, hmm?
有个穿着万圣节服装和披风的疯子
Some nutjob in a Halloween costume and cape
闯进咱们家  还干掉了我们四位兄弟
comes into our house and takes out four of our brothers?!
他用这个对付我们警监
He does this to our captain?!
我已经干这行很久了
Now, I've been around a long time.
就好像这座城市的坏人
It's like the bad guys in this town
变得越来越怪了
just keep getting weirder and weirder,
但那面具之下
but under that mask...
只是个人
is just a man,
他也会流血
and he can bleed,
就像你和我一样
just like you and me,
而如果他会流血  他就可以被打倒
and if he bleeds, he can be beaten.
所以  我们去做
So, let's do what the cap
警监也会让我们去做的事
would tell us to do if he were here.
我们出去
Let's go out there
找到那狗娘养的
and let's find that son of a bitch
不惜一切代价  抓到他
and let's get him, whatever it takes!
我不适合做演讲
I'm not one for speeches.
不不不  你做得很好
No, no, no, you did fine.
但是
But?
如果我看到的那个是盖勒文
If that was Galavan that I saw,
他会知道如何隐藏
he'll know how to stay out of sight.
我们思维得灵活点
We got to think outside the box.
譬如呢
Like what?
谁最了解他并且还在城里
Who knows him best who's still in the city?
他妹妹
His sister.
阿尔弗雷德  停车
Alfred, pull over.
布鲁斯少爷  你的小脑袋瓜失去理智了吗
Master Bruce, are you out of your tiny, bloody mind?
有个疯子在街上乱跑
There's a madman loose on the streets.
现在可不是你独自行动的时候  不是吗
Now is not the time to go running around on your own, is it?
我没打算独自行动
I don't plan on being on my own.
无意冒犯  少爷
With all due respect, sir,
如果盖勒文真出现了
what good will a 15-year-old little girl do
15岁小女孩又能怎样
even if Galavan does turn up?
斯特兰奇欺骗了警察
Strange lied to the police.
我很清楚  你也一样
I know it, a-and so do you.
我不能待在家里  无所事事
I can't stay at home and do nothing.
我们得信任吉姆·戈登
We need to trust Jim Gordon.
我厌倦了信任吉姆·戈登  你没有吗
I'm tired of trusting Jim Gordon, aren't you?
我是你的监护人  布鲁斯少爷
I am your guardian, Master Bruce,
我的任务就是保护你
and it is my job to protect you.
看我袖手旁观无所事事也是你的任务吗
Is it your job to watch me sit on my hands and do nothing?
阿尔弗雷德  求你
Alfred, please.
让我去吧
Let me go.
老兄  把车移开
Hey, buddy, move your car!
那...要当心  好吗
Just... just be careful, all right?
我会的
I will.
快点
Hey, let's go!
好啦  伙计...
Yeah, all right, mate, keep...
别着急啊
just keep your bloody hair on!
别走  宝贝  求你  咱俩谈谈
Don't go, baby, come on, let's talk about this, huh?
是因为我把芭芭拉赶出去了吗
Is this because I-I kicked Barbara out?
让我走  布奇
Just let me go, Butch.
拜托  我什么都听你的
Come on, I'll do whatever you want.
我会多吃水果  少打呼噜
I-I-I'll eat more fruit. I-I'll work on the snoring,
我发誓  都听你的
I swear to God, whatever you need...
不方便吗
Catch you guys at a bad time?
真是的  你们都怎么进来的
Seriously, how do people keep getting in here?!
我这儿连个保安都没有吗
Do I have no security at all?!
急什么
Why the rush?
该向前看了
Just time to move on.
是吗
Oh, yeah, is that it?
还是你担心盖勒文也会来报复你
Or are you worried Galavan's coming after you, too?
别担心  布奇
Don't worry, Butch.
不是你的问题
It's not about you.
她只是害怕她哥哥
She's just scared of her brother.
帮我找到他吧
Come on, help me find him.
你俩最后也是不欢而散
You two hardly left on the best of terms.
很怪吧  看见自己死去的哥哥
Must have been weird, seeing your dead brother
穿得像个中世纪的忍者冒出来
show up dressed like a ninja from Medieval Times.
昨晚刺伤你们警监的那个东西
That thing that stabbed your captain last night...
不是我哥
wasn't my brother.
是一个三百年前的刺客  叫阿泽瑞尔
It was a 300-year-old assassin called Azrael.
阿泽瑞尔
Azrael?
我在新闻上看到的画面
That image I saw on the news,
他的装束  行动方式
his clothes, the way he moved...
是阿泽瑞尔
it was Azrael.
是抚养我哥长大的那些僧侣
A mythical figure worshipped by the monks
崇拜的一个神话人物
who raised my brother.
一个冷血杀手  夜晚出没
A cold-hearted killing machine sent into the night
奉命去杀他主人的敌人
to kill his master's enemies...
而他想杀你
and he wants you.
一个古代刺客
An ancient assassin?
一个传奇
A legend.
我家人以前常讲他的故事
My family used to tell stories of him.
他是真人
He was real?
谁知道
Who knows.
三百年前的事了
It was 300 years ago.
也许是吧
Probably, yes.
这么说  你哥疯了吗
So, your brother's gone nuts?
你说呢
You tell me.
西奥昨晚的行为使你相信他是阿泽瑞尔
Theo convince you that he was Azrael last night,
还是他在演戏
or was he acting?
有人给我哥洗脑了
Someone got inside my brother's head.
那里可不安全
It's not a safe place to be.
如果你说对了  那我想找到此人
If you're right, I want to find this person,
但首先  我得找到你哥
but first I have to find your brother...
帮帮我吧
so help me.
如果搜查队找到他  会杀了他的
If a search team finds him, they're gonna kill him.
他终归还是你哥
He is still your brother, after all.
血亲
He's blood.
他昨晚用的剑  断了的那把
The sword that was used last night, the one that broke...
是把假剑
it was fake.
你怎么知道的
And you know this how?
那把真剑是我祖父的
The real one belonged to my grandfather.
他是个古董收藏家  对杜马家族史很痴迷
He was an antiquities collector, obsessed with Dumas history.
我见过一次  很漂亮
I saw it once; it was beautiful.
僧侣们自己铸造的
Forged by the monks themselves.
据说此剑蕴含神力
It's said to hold supernatural powers.
西奥知道这点
Theo knew this.
他可能会想偷回来
It's possible he'll attempt to steal it back.
还在你爷爷手上吗
Does your grandfather still have it?
他现在在哪
And where is he?
哥谭公墓
Gotham Cemetery.
他二十年前已经去世了
He's been dead for 20 years...
但他的财宝随他陪葬了
but he was buried with his treasures.
塞琳娜
Selina?
你好吗
'Sup?
我记得你告诉过我
I remember you telling me
你还在喂你朋友的鸟
you're still feeding your friend's birds.
总得有人照顾它们
Someone has to.
你为什么来这里
Why you here?
你看新闻了吗
Have you seen the news?
哥谭有行尸吗
Walking zombies in Gotham?
有什么大惊小怪的
What's new?
斯特兰奇曾为我父亲一个旨在帮助他人的项目工作
Strange worked for my father on a project designed to help people.
但他扭曲了其目的  现在我认为他找到了...
He perverted it and now I believe he's found a way to...
复活死人的办法
Bring back the dead?
有点异想天开吧
A little far-fetched, don't you think?
也许吧  但他肯定有所隐瞒
Perhaps, but he's hiding something.
警察查不到
The police failed to find out what.
我觉得我能查到
I think I can do better.
是吗
That so?
我父亲叫停斯特兰奇的项目后  他就被杀了
When my father shut down Strange, he was killed.
塞琳娜  我只是想知道真相而已
Selina, I just want the truth, that's all.
你就是不见棺材不落泪  是吧
You just won't be happy until you get yourself killed, will you?
维克多·弗莱斯和西奥·盖勒文去阿卡姆时
Victor Fries and Theo Galavan both went to Arkham
都是死人了  两个人都活了
as dead men. Both returned.
我不在乎
I don't care.
你朋友布莉姬特也是
So did your friend Bridget.
等等  他们把她送去阿卡姆了
Wait, they sent her to Arkham?
她现在可能还在那里
She may still be there right now.
还活着
Alive.
我叫她离开这座城市的
I told her to leave town,
逃得远远的  但她不听
to run, but she didn't listen.
都怪我
It's my fault she's there.
塞琳娜  我们能弥补这件事
Selina, we can put this right.
斯特兰奇做好了应付警方的准备
Strange was ready for the police.
他甚至可能有内部线报
He may even have been tipped off.
唯一能查清真相的办法...
The only way we're gonna find out what's really going on in there...
就是我们自己闯进去
is if we break in ourselves.
闯进去
Break in?
闯进阿卡姆
To Arkham?
一个满是疯子的高度警戒设施
A highly guarded place that's packed with crazy people?
如果你觉得太危险  我就自己去吧
If it's too dangerous for you, I'll just go myself.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
监狱都是设计防止人越狱的  而不是闯入
Prisons are meant to stop people from breaking out, not in.
这是可以做到的
It can be done.
那里是疯人院  不是监狱
It's a loony bin, not a prison.
我知道能做到
I know it can be done.
但我要一个人去
But I go alone.
为什么
Why?
如果我被逮到  他们至多把我丢出来
If I get caught, they'll just toss me out.
没人在乎我
Nobody cares about me.
但你呢
But you?
他们看到你来了  会马上关掉整个设施
They see you coming and they'll shut that whole thing down
你都来不及通风报信
quicker than you can say "Rat."
那你就永远别想查明他们在做什么了
And then you'll never find out what they've been up to.
或者
That or...
他们会直接杀了你
they'll just kill you.
再说
Besides...
我已经有条进去的路了
I already know a way in.
就是这里
This is it.
杜马墓穴
The Dumas crypt.
我好多亲戚都埋在这里
Dozens of my relatives are buried here.
有人有钥匙吗
So does someone have a key?
好吧  钥匙  撬棒  一回事
All right. Key, crowbar.
这个
This one.
我祖父的
My grandfather's.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我们这样肯定违反了很多法律
I'm sure we're breaking more than a few laws right now.
不是吧  这个你就接受不了吗
Really? This is where you draw the line?
拜托
Come on.
你难道丝毫不觉得恐怖吗
This doesn't creep you out, even a little bit?
这可是盗墓
It's friggin' grave robbing!
不惜一切  哈维
Whatever it takes, Harvey.
帮帮忙
Little help?
据说那是阿泽瑞尔一直用的剑
That was said to be Azrael's sword up until the end.
他死了
He died?
不  他消失了
No, he disappeared.
阿泽瑞尔被认为是永生者
Azrael's thought to be immortal.
真美
It's beautiful.
给我吧
I will take that.
詹姆斯·戈登
James Gordon.
你
Time...
该
to...
死了
die!
让开  他必须死
Step aside. He must die.
是我啊  哥哥
It's me, brother.
你不认得我吗
Don't you recognize me?
我跟你无仇
My quarrel is not with you.
让开
Step aside.
塔比莎
Tabitha.
你妹妹
Your sister.
你要的东西在我这儿
I have what you're looking for.
塔比莎
Tabitha?
没错
That's right.
记得我们一起长大的地方吗
You remember where we grew up?
海边的那栋房子
The estate by the sea?
那是僧侣带走你之前
Before the monks took you.
我们的狗  我们的马
Our dogs, the horses?
我们曾那么开心
We were happy once.
你是西奥·盖勒文
You are Theo Galavan.
我哥哥
My brother.
西奥
Theo?
没错
Yes.
新市长  西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan, the new mayor...!
你记起来了吗
Do you remember now?
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
布鲁斯·韦恩
Bruce Wayne.
我们被派去杀他
We were sent to kill him.
是的  但是
Yes, yes, but...
他侮辱了我们家族的名誉
He dishonored our family name.
是的
Yes.
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
谢谢你提醒了我
Thank you for reminding me.
叛徒
Traitor.
哈维
Harvey?
他跑了
He's gone!
这里是布洛克
This is Bullock.
马上前来墓园增援
I need a backup down at the cemetery.
盖勒文又跑了
Galavan's in the wind again.
好了
Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我让他记起来了
I made him remember.
记起来什么了
Remember what?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
"死神降临哥谭之子"
"Death to the Son of Gotham."
陪着她
Stay with her.
我得去找到布鲁斯
I need to find Bruce.
停车
Slow down!
我需要这辆车
I need this car.
-你已经不是警察了  戈登  -车给我
- You ain't a cop anymore, Gordon. - I need the damn car!
阿卡姆疯人院
快接  快接
Come on, come on.
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce?
不  是我  布鲁斯呢
No, it's me. Where's Bruce?
我不知道  他进城了
I don't know. He was in the city.
城里什么地方
Where in the city?
老实说  我完全不知道
Well, to be perfectly honest, I haven't got the foggiest.
那小子现在自有主意
He's got a mind of his own at the moment, that one, doesn't he?
好吧  我们得找到他
All right, well, we need to find him.
盖勒文可能要去杀他
Galavan could be coming after him.
你开玩笑呢吧  他不是在追杀你吗
Well, you're having a laugh, ain't you? I thought he was after you.
本来是的  但塔比莎激起了他的记忆
He was. Tabitha must have jogged his memory.
让他想起了他原本的任务
Reminded him of his original mission:
杀布鲁斯·韦恩
kill Bruce Wayne.
好吧  那我去开车
Right. Well, I'll-I'll get the motor.
不不  你待在那儿
No, no, no. You stay there
以防他回来
in case he comes back.
你最后在城里什么地方见到他的
Where was the last place you saw him in the city?
柯林斯和德莱尼街街口
Uh, Collins and Delaney.
我最后见到他时  他正要上楼顶
Last I saw of him, he was headed for the roof
应该是去见塞琳娜了
to see that Selina, I reckon.
好  我去那边
All right, I'll head over there.
到时再说  你小心
Till then, be safe.
好嘞
Righto.
没问题
Will do.
老天爷啊  布鲁斯少爷
Oh, for Pete's sake, Master Bruce.
这么偷偷摸摸的  我差点没切了你
Creeping up on someone like that, I could have filleted you.
抱歉
Sorry.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
盖勒文  布鲁斯少爷
Galavan, Master Bruce.
西奥·盖勒文要来了
Theo bloody Galavan is what's wrong.
好了  好了
Okay. Okay.
老天爷
Holy cow!
法医男
Forensic guy?
-街头女  -你陷害了戈登
- Street trash girl? - You framed Gordon.
-你还想供出他拿赏钱呢  -是啊
- And you tried to get a reward by turning him in. - Oh, yeah.
你怎么在这儿
What the hell are you doing here?
我要逃出去  这地方简直疯了
I got to get out of here. This place is crazy.
他们大概在找我  走哪能出去
They're probably looking for me. Which way is out of here?
你帮我  我就帮你
I'll help you if you help me.
斯特兰奇在哪
Where's Strange right now?
好吧  听着  我跟你不熟
Okay, look, I barely know you,
但你绝对不想去找他
but that is the last person that you want to be looking for.
为什么
Why is that?
这里的地下室
The basement here,
太可怕了
it's horrible.
相信我  千万别靠近
Just trust me, stay away.
-他是个非常危险的人  -地下室
- He's a very dangerous man. - Basement?
活人  死人
Alive people, dead people,
死活人  太可怕了
dead-alive people-- it's horrible.
-好吧  我怎么过去  -我说话
- Okay, how do I get there? - Wow, it's like I'm saying things,
你好像完全没听到
and you're just not hearing them.
他抓了我一个朋友  我是来救她的
He has a friend of mine, and I'm here to get her out.
我怎么过去
Now, how... do... I get... there?
你会告诉我怎么出去
You'll tell me the way out?
是的
Yes.
好吧
Okay.
有个电梯
There's an elevator.
我会告诉你在哪  但是
I'll tell you where it is, but...
你会撬锁吗
can you pick a lock?
你为什么非要逞英雄
Why'd you have to be brave, huh?
我都习惯了有你在身边
I just got used to you being around.
搭档  是吧
Partners, right?
我现在要怎么管住别人啊
How am I supposed to keep people in line now, huh?
我觉得没有你我做不到
I don't think I can do this without you.
你是这世上唯一
You're one of the only people in the world
跟我说话时看着我眼睛的人
who looks me in the eye when they talk to me.
知道吗
You know that?
我讲笑话你会笑
You laugh at my jokes.
你喜欢我的样子
You actually like the way I look.
我以为我再不会有这样的感觉了
I didn't think I'd ever feel like this again.
我猜我想说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is...
别停下啊  我眼眶刚要湿了
Well, don't stop now. I was just getting misty.
你来做什么
What are you doin' here?
表示一下心意
Paying my respects.
我得说  她有点憔悴
She's looked better, I must say.
你别想伤害她
You will not hurt her.
我为什么要伤害她
Why would I do that?
我知道
I know.
因为她从背后捅死了我妈妈
Because she stabbed my mother in the back!
你敢碰她  我杀了你
If you touch her, I will kill you.
我喜欢你这个新的一面
I like this new side of you.
心软  多情
Soft, sentimental.
他必须付出代价  布奇
He has to pay, Butch.
谁
Who?
阿泽瑞尔吗
Azrael?
不  盖勒文
No! Galavan!
你瞧  我绝不相信这套超级坏蛋的扯淡
See, I will not buy this whole uber-villain nonsense.
如果他想穿皮衣
I mean, if he wanted to wear leather,
那就穿皮衣好了
he should just wear leather.
这里可是哥谭  谁在乎呢
This is Gotham City. No one cares, right?
我们都曾因他受苦
We have all suffered by his hand.
我
Me,
你
you,
我母亲
my mother.
现在  还有他亲妹妹
And now his own sister.
盖勒文必须死
Galavan must die.
到时候
And when he does,
你就放过我们吗
you'll leave us alone?
或许吧
I suppose.
保证
Promise.
天呐
Geez.
好吧  我保证
Fine. Yes.
随你了
Whatever.
他在哪
Where is he?!
喂
Yeah.
他在这儿
He's here,
安全
and he's safe.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
我就来
I'm coming.
你对我不仅仅是个监护人  阿尔弗雷德
You're more to me than just a guardian, Alfred.
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
你这时机挑的真是
Your timing really is quite...
太好了  布鲁斯少爷
impeccable, Master Bruce.
但我们现在没时间
But we haven't got time for...
多愁善感
sentimental nonsense right now.
我们得确保所有门都锁好了
We have to make sure that all the doors are locked,
窗户都关好了  灯都熄灭了
all the windows are closed, and the lights are off
尽可能让盖勒文不好找到我们
to make it as hard as possible for Galavan to find us,
明白吗
do you get me?
戈登警探确定他会来这儿吗
Detective Gordon's sure he's coming here?
没什么事是确定的
Nothing's certain, is it?
我们得做好准备
So we need to be ready.
好
Okay.
房子很大  我们该分头行动
It's a big house. We should split up.
好吧
Fine.
但你动作快点
But just you be quick.
你负责楼上
So, you take the upstairs.
我负责楼下
I will take the downstairs.
你把窗户都关好
You make sure the windows are closed.
把门都锁上
You make sure the doors are locked.
把天窗也都关上
You make sure the skylights are closed.
然后尽快下来书房跟我汇合
And then you meet me down here as quick as you can in the study,
好吗  去吧
all right? Now go.
阿尔弗雷德  阿尔弗雷德
Alfred! Alfred!
真聪明
Ingenious.
你
You,
你要带我去见那男孩
you will show me to the boy.
除非我死了
Over my dead body.
如你所愿
As you wish.
那是什么声音
What's that noise?
爱德  那是什么声音
Hey, Ed. What's that noise?
尼格玛
Nygma!
该死的
Son of a...
尼格玛
Nygma.
拉警报
Sound the alarm.
有人逃跑
We got a runner!
快走
Go!
快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on.
太好了
Okay, great.
好了
Okay.
阿尔弗雷德  阿尔弗雷德
Alfred! Alfred...
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
再踏一步  伙计
Take one more step, mate,
我就一枪打在你眼睛之间
and I will put a bullet right between your bloody eyes.
你觉得这就能阻止我了吗  男仆
You think that'll stop me, manservant?
如果你不介意  我打算试试
I'd like to give it a go, if you don't mind.
你以为我是血肉之躯吗  我是永生者
Think I'm flesh and blood? I am immortal
我厌倦你了
and I have grown tired of you!
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
快跑  布鲁斯
Run, Bruce!
永生  那我们试试看吧
Immortal? Let's see, shall we?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred!
快走  快走
Come on, come on.
请给我们点时间
Give us a minute, please.
我想可以说阿泽瑞尔已经失控了
I think we can safely say Azrael has gone rogue.
我还不想妄下这种结论
I'm not comfortable making that assumption just yet.
但他已经24小时没跟我们联络了
But it's been more than 24 hours since he's made contact.
或许是因为吉姆·戈登还没死
Perhaps that's because Jim Gordon still breathes.
但如果警方先抓住了他  我们要如何解释
But if the police catch him first, how do we explain...
一件无法解释的事吗
Something that cannot be explained?
我们不用
We don't.
西奥·盖勒文已经不在了
Theo Galavan is no more.
阿泽瑞尔是他的新身份
Azrael is his new creation.
一个杀手  一个疯子
A killer, a madman.
哥谭市警局想抓住他  只会以失败告终
The GCPD will fail if they try to capture him.
他们只能杀了他  到时候
They'll have to kill him first. And when they do,
他们就等于替我们掩盖了踪迹
they'll be successfully covering our tracks for us.
现在  这间设施得关闭
In the meantime, this facility needs to be shut down.
所有实验对象转移去新地点
All subjects moved to the new location.
已经在办了
Already happening.
这就对了
That's my girl.
该死
Damn it.
别躲啊  小男孩
Don't hide, little boy.
出来面对我
Face me.
面对死亡
Face... death.
你知道韦恩家族曾是这城市的弊病吗
You know the Waynes were a blight upon this city?
一个自私
A selfish,
自大的家族
arrogant family.
没有信仰的家族
A family with no beliefs.
没有荣誉感
No honor.
不知尊敬
No respect.
你是你父亲的独子  布鲁斯
You're your father's only son, Bruce.
等我杀了你
When I kill you,
我就将彻底铲除
I eradicate the Wayne name...
韦恩一族
forever.
就好像你从未存在过
It will be as though you had never existed.
游戏玩够了
Enough fun and games.
受死吧
Prepare to die.
没想到
Unexpected.
你没事吧
You okay?
抱歉我没能早点赶过来
Sorry I couldn't get here sooner.
看来我错过了全部的精彩
Seems like I missed all the fun.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
我不是替你拖住他了吗
I slowed him down for you, didn't I?
我呼叫布洛克
I'll call Bullock.
我该教你开车了  布鲁斯少爷
Time I taught you how to drive, Master Bruce.
你现在该知道了
You should know by now
子弹是杀不死这个怪物的  吉姆
that bullets don't kill this monster, Jim.
我上把伞插在你喉咙里了
My last one got stuck in your throat,
所以  这把我想捅进别的地方里
so I'm thinking about shoving this one somewhere else.
吉姆  下次记住
Jim, a little tip for next time:
干活儿一定要带对工具
always bring the right tools for the job.
地狱见了  西奥
See you in hell, Theo.
不客气
You're welcome.
走吧  布奇
Let's go, Butch.
再见  各位
Good night, fellas.
我的天
Oh, my God...
那小丫头没说错
That little sprite was right.
别动
Freeze.
待着别动
Remain where you are.
天呐
Oh, dear.
你是我的受试人吗
Are you my human subject?
什么
What?
你是被派来测试我的吗
Were you sent here to test me?
布莉姬特
Bridget?
布莉姬特是谁
Who's Bridget?
是我啊  塞琳娜
It's me, Selina.
什么
What?
警察抓你的时候  你烧伤了自己  记得吗
You burnt yourself when the cops tried to bust you, remember?
我不记得任何此前的事
I don't remember anything before this.
斯特兰奇教授说我患了失忆症
Professor Strange told me I had amnesia.
不  别信任他
No, don't trust him.
你叫布莉姬特
Your name's Bridget.
他说过会派人来测试我
He told me he'd send people to test me.
我不是来测试你的  我是来带你回家的
Well, I'm not here to test you. I'm here to take you home.
他说过你会这么说
That's what he said you'd say.
布莉姬特  别
Bridget, no, Bridget, no,
布莉姬特  别  布莉姬特  别
Bridget, no, Bridget, no, Bridget, no!
布莉姬特  别
Bridget, no.
别那么喊我
Don't call me that.
我叫
My name's...
萤火虫
Firefly.